JOSHUA BEE

9 Auction Close Burstwick Hull East Riding of Yorkshire HU12 9DB Telephone: 07915 107162 E-mail: joshuaregular@gmail.com Website: joshuabee.github.io

PERSONAL STATEMENT

I am a conscientious, ambitious and hard-working software developer, aiming to establish myself as a leader in problem solving. I am a quick learner, which has been evidenced by teaching myself all the programming languages that I know. I would flourish in an environment where I can learn more languages to increase my knowledge further.

EMPLOYMENT

2019-Present META

Senior Software Developer

META is a digital agency specialising in search marketing and ecommerce, with a specific interest in Shopify. As a senior software developer I was responsible for creating and maintaining Shopify Apps, RESTful APIs and services to solve many interesting problems.

- Built agile development processes to allow the company to grow with the correct culture.
 Used Azure DevOps to implement continuous deployment and integration to automate build, test and release projects.
- Worked closely with clients on the whole project lifecycle, from initiation to completion, to make sure the functionality was built to their specific needs.
- Developed the following Shopify Apps and APIs:
 - App to allow customers to checkout using a new finance provider, circumventing the conventional checkout process.
 - App to allow trade customers to checkout with an invoice, delaying payment until a more suitable time for the customer.
 - Automatically generate UPS shipping labels when an order is created.
 - Update Google Analytics when an order is refunded after using finance.
 - Use Microsoft Custom Vision AI to match customer's pictures of dream wedding dresses to clients' actual stock.

2012-2018 Symphony RetailAl

Software Developer

Symphony RetailAI is a fast moving consumer goods business with a focus on technology. As a developer I was responsible for creating programs to help retailers and manufacturers increase their revenue through data driven analysis.

- Project leader for a program that analyses nationwide product distributions, and is currently being used by 2 international clients. Improved the usability of the application and implemented solutions to meet customer needs.
- Developed a cloud based application that encompasses all aspects of product execution, including; assortment, space planning and store planning modules.
- Implemented database structuring and optimisation techniques to make the applications run as quickly and faultlessly as possible.

EDUCATION

2018-2019 University of Hull Master of Research

Computer Science

Worked on a yearlong Master of Research degree focusing on developing novel techniques to improve the efficiency of Generative Adversarial Networks, a framework of Artificial Neural Networks.

2009-2012 University of Nottingham Bachelor of Science with Honours

Applied Mathematics
First Class

Modules undertaken include: Applied Mathematics (88), Calculus (88), Differential Equations (70), Linear Mathematics (86), Modelling with Differential Equations (93), Topics in Scientific Computation (79) and Vector Calculus (84).

2007-2009 Colchester Sixth Form College

A-Level: Mathematics (A) Further Mathematics (A) Chemistry (A)

AS-Level: Geology (B) Economics (C)

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Backend languages: C#, Delphi, Java and Python and SQL Server.
- Frontend languages: CSS, HTML, JavaScript (React, Node) and PHP.
- Azure DevOps: Boards, Repos and Pipelines.
- Proficient use of Microsoft Word, Excel and PowerPoint.
- Full clean driving licence.

ACTIVITIES AND INTERESTS

- Currently developing a website for a local football team.
- Regularly play football, squash, badminton and table tennis.
- Play the guitar, bass guitar and drums.